Guide to the Tavern Guild of San Francisco Records, 1961-1993
Tavern Guild of San Francisco Records,
- Events, 1961-1993, Series 6:; 1 Box, 7 Folders
  - General Event Information (Box-folder 15/30-15/34)
    - Ordinance Regarding the Regulation of Poker Games, n.d. (Box-folder 15/32)
    - Alcoholic Beverage Control (ABC), 1961-1991, n.d. (Box-folder 15/33)
    - Vendors, 1973, n.d. (Box-folder 15/34)
- Programs and Projects, 1973-1992, n.d., Series 7:; 2 Boxes, 7 Folders
  This series contains material relating to a number of community service projects and programs with which the TGSF/SFTGF was involved.
  - Godfather Service Fund, 1984-1989, Subseries A:; 8 Folders
    This subseries concerns the Godfather Service Fund (GSF), an all-volunteer AIDS support program and "a standing committee of the San Francisco Tavern Guild Foundation." Financial information, correspondence, minutes, and publicity materials from the GSF reveal the methods by which this committee raised money and dispensed care packages to AIDS patients in various hospitals around San Francisco. Of particular interest in the Correspondence folder are thank-you notes from patients and patients' families. Included are special events with which they were involved as beneficiaries, such as the AIDS Bike-a-thon, several beer busts, and a Solo Supermarket event.
    - Minutes, 1985-1986 (Box-folder 16/1)
    - Correspondence, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 16/2)
    - Financial (Box-folder 16/3-16/4)
      - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 16/3)
      - 1987-1989 (Box-folder 16/4)
    - General, 1985-1988 (Box-folder 16/5)
    - Sunday Brunches, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 16/6)
    - Bike-a-Thon (Box-folder 16/7-16/8)
      - 1985-1986 (Box-folder 16/7)
      - 1987 (Box-folder 16/8)
  - Community Thrift Store, 1982-1992, n.d., Subseries B:; 1 Box, 2 Folders
    This subseries documents the establishment, administration, and work of the Community Thrift Store. Materials include quarterly financial statements, correspondence, news releases, legal material, documents relating to tax status, receipts, bank statements, profit distribution lists, memos, flyers, clippings, an employee manual, and a Thrift Store Operations Agreement. Three Polaroids of Double Feature Video, the proposed location for a satellite operation called Community Thrift Bookstore, have been moved to the photographs series. One folder (approx. 1.5") of Organization Histories details the amounts paid to each participating organization from 1989-1994.
    - Financial (Box-folder 16/9-17/5)
      - Reports 1-9A, 1982-1983 (Box-folder 16/9)
      - Reports 10-15, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 17/1)
      - 1987-1989 (Box-folder 17/2)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 17/3)
      - 1991 (Box-folder 17/4)
      - 1992 (Box-folder 17/5)
    - General (Box-folder 17/6-17/13)
      - 1982 (Box-folder 17/6)
      - 1983 (Box-folder 17/7)
      - 1984 (Box-folder 17/8)
      - 1984, **RESTRICTED until 2039** (Box-folder 17/9)
      - 1985 (Box-folder 17/10)
      - 1990 (Box-folder 17/11)
      - 1991-1992, n.d. (Box-folder 17/12)
      - 1991, **RESTRICTED until 2046** (Box-folder 17/13)
    - Organization Histories, 1991 (Box-folder 18/1)
  - Other Programs and Projects, 1973-1990, n.d., Subseries C:; 6 Folders
    This subseries includes documents relating to six programs and projects of the TGSF/SFTGF.
    The AIDS Hospice Campaign:
    memoranda, clippings, and proposals about the establishment of the campaign
    East Bay AIDS Fund (also called the East Bay Assistance Fund):
    financial documentation, correspondence, and case files relating to auctions and other fundraising activities
    Imperial Court:
    documentation relating to campaigning and voting, as well as some financial material
    LAST CALL:
    a letter regarding an organization called Learning Alcohol Service Techniques for Control Against Liquor Liability
    Operation Concern:
    constitution and by-laws, financial documentation, and correspondence relating to raising funds for mental health care
    San Francisco Prevention Project:
    material from a workshop series to prevent substance abuse
    - AIDS Hospice Campaign, 1984 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - East Bay AIDS Fund/East Bay Assistance Fund, 1984-1986, n.d. (Box-folder 18/3)
    - Imperial Court, 1974-1990, n.d. (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Last Call, 1989 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - Operation Concern, 1985 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - San Francisco Prevention Project Workshop Series, 1973-1977 (Box-folder 18/7)
- Political Subject Files, 1963-1991, n.d., Series 8:; 14 Folders
  This series includes files on political topics of importance to the Tavern Guild such as material from the San Francisco Human Rights Commission relating to racial discrimination within the gay community.
  - Human Rights Commission Hiring Discrimination, 1984-1985 (Box-folder 18/8)
  - Racism and Discrimination in San Francisco Gay Bars, 1982-1985, n.d. (Box-folder 18/9)
  - Community Guild Business Association, 1974 (Box-folder 18/10)
  - Orange Juice Boycott, 1977 (Box-folder 19/1)
  - California Hall, 1965 (Box-folder 19/2)
  - Citizen's Alert, n.d. (Box-folder 19/3)
  - Golden Gate Gay Liberation House, 1976, n.d. (Box-folder 19/4)
  - Coors, ca. 1991 (Box-folder 19/5)
  - Gays in the Military, 1966, n.d. (Box-folder 19/6)
  - Mattachine Society, 1963, 1966, n.d. (Box-folder 19/7)
  - Central City Community Organization, 1973-1974 (Box-folder 20/8)
  - Guidelines for Establishment of a Legal Defense Fund for the Gay Community, 1974 (Box-folder 20/9)
  - Order Denying Rehearing in Case of Various Homophile Groups v. Pacific Telephone and Telegraph, 1970 (Box-folder 20/10)
  - Miscellaneous Political, 1973-1989, n.d. (Box-folder 19/8)
- Administrative and Miscellaneous, 1964-1993, n.d., Series 9:; 16 Folders
  This series includes material relating to running the TGSF office, bad check lists, a San Francisco Bar Directory advertising order form, and health insurance information. In addition, this series contains flyers, notes, clippings, press releases, and legal documentation. The second folder of clippings in this series contains an entire issue of the San Francisco Banner that published a large number of Fictitious Business Name Statements that list the names and addresses of business owners and their businesses.
  - TGSF Blank Letterhead, n.d. (Box-folder 19/9)
  - Application for Employment Listing, 1989 (Box-folder 19/10)
  - Tavern Guild Office Administration, 1986, n.d. (Box-folder 19/11)
  - Bar Directory Advertising Order Form, n.d. (Box-folder 19/12)
  - Bad Check Lists, 1971, n.d. (Box-folder 19/13)
  - Health Insurance for The Spoiled Brat, Inc., 1984-1985 (Box-folder 19/14)
  - Information Bulletin Regarding Charitable Solicitation, 1985 (Box-folder 19/15)
  - Capitol Tire Offer to Members of the SFTG, n.d. (Box-folder 19/16)
  - Notes, 1993, n.d. (Box-folder 19/17)
  - Legal Documents, 1978, 1982 (Box-folder 19/18)
  - Clippings 1/2, 1964-1983, n.d. (Box-folder 19/19)
  - Clippings 2/2, 1978 (Box-folder 19/20)
  - Polk Street Slaying, 1974 (Box-folder 19/21)
  - San Francisco Tavern Guild Press Releases, 1977 (Box-folder 19/22)
  - Wayne Friday Speech about Harvey Milk, n.d. (Box-folder 19/23)
  - Miscellaneous, 1969-1990, n.d. (Box-folder 19/24)
- Photographs, n.d., Series 10:; 2 Folders
  This series includes color portraits of past presidents, including Don Banks, Dick Gersbach, Bill Plath, and Darryl Glied. It also includes unidentified portraits and events. Identifiable figures include Dianne Feinstein and Harvey Milk. In addition, this series contains three Polaroids removed from the Community Thrift Subseries and two photos of the Community Thrift store at 623 Valencia before and after painting.
  - Seven 11X14 photos of past presidents, n.d. (Box C Oversize Photo)
  - Miscellaneous Photographs, n.d. (Box 2 of Photos from Manuscript Collections)
- Banners, n.d., Series 11:; 1 Box
  This series includes four banners, each approximately 3 ft. by 10 ft. All are made of brownish-orange canvas and blue painted lettering, with grommets around the edge for hanging. One says "Tavern", another "Guild", both in plain lettering. A third says "Welcome" in Medieval-style lettering. The fourth has the Tavern Guild logo on the left one-third of the banner.
  - 4 banners, n.d. (Box 21)